Muhammad Usman

React Developer

House No. 84 I-block Shah Rukne Alam Colony, Multan (+92) 337 6024922 usmangq12@gmail.com linkedin.com/muhammad-usman github.com/usmangq12 twitter.com/Muhammad-Usman

I'm a community-taught developer with 4 plus years of experience. I love reading and enhancing my knowledge day by day, and love to solve complex problems. I'm always ready for new challenges which keep me motivated to move on in the coding field at another level.

EXPERIENCE

SHARE Mobility, Columbus, United States

Senior React Developer, Remote

September 2020 - PRESENT

- Helped craft the driving module for Ride-Hailing. Created booking rides, rate-ride, referral-reward.
- Built optimized routes system for admin panel using Google Maps API.
- Created auto-response back system based on AI using Twilio.

Geminus.AI, Palo Alto, California, United States

React Developer, Remote

JULY 2019 – August 2020

- Supervised team of 3 developers engaged in Front-end development.
- Built dashboards to visualize Functional Gas Stations data. Created admin dashboard for municipal corporation system by developing alarm system using MQTT service.
- Created visuals to help identify leaks, pressure drops, and other potential problems.

Curiato, Canada

React Developer, Remote

October 2017 - June 2019

- Developed highly customized charts using D3 to visualize the clinical conditions of the patient.
- Created interactive visuals on PowerBI to express different clinical metrics.

EDUCATION

University Of Education, Lahore Campus Multan – BSIT

Skills

- Languages (JavaScript, Typescript, Java)
- JavaScript Frameworks (React, Next.js, Vue)
- Databases (MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL)
- Visualizations (D3.js, PowerBI)
- near-api-js
- Performance Optimization (SSR, Memoization)
- Git actions
- CSS frameworks (Bootstrap, Material, Ant design, Tailwind)
- Backend architecture (Express)

Personal Projects

Sensors-APP (React, Typescript, recharts, material-table, axios, Express, PostgreSQL)

Built a dashboard to display charts and tables against the real-time sensors collected data fetched by Sensors-API.

usmangq12/sensors-app

usmangq12/sensors-api

CURRENCY-CALCULATOR (React, styled-components, react-redux, redux-saga, react-table)

Created header with base currency (to be used on all the routes), the first component where base currency, target currency dropdowns, and amount field is shown to get desired results. The currency exchange grid is added on another component against the header selected base currency to see all of its currency rates.

usmangq12/currency-converter

Activities

I love to play cricket on weekends. I always keep engage myself in the community to learn more from others experiences. I keep myself updated with the new technologies and motivated by reading books. Nowadays, I'm focused to learn web3.